(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-31T08:28:12.722550",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
周防パトラ 誕生日3Dライブ 2025
[Suou Patra Birthday 3D LIVE 2025]
燃え上がれ
Fire up!
燃え上がれ ガンダム
Fire up, Gundam!
君よ走れ
You, run!
まだ怒りに燃える 闘志があるなら
If you still have a fighting spirit...
巨大な敵を 討てよ 討てよ 討てよ
Strike down the giant enemy!
正義の怒りを ぶつけろ ガンダム
Strike with the rage of justice, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam, Gundam!
立ち上がれ 立ち上がれ 立ち上がれ ガンダム
Stand up! Stand up! Stand up, Gundam!
君よ叫べ
You, shout!
まだ絶望に沈む 悲しみにあるなら
If you still have sadness...
恐怖をはらんで 行けよ 行けよ 行けよ
Face the fear and go, go, go!
うず巻く血潮を 燃やせ ガンダム
Burn the swirling tide of blood, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam, Gundam!
翔べよ 翔べよ 翔べよ ガンダム
Fly, fly, fly, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam, Gundam!
みなさん！ 周防パトラ生誕3Dライブにお越しいただいて、どうもありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you for coming to Suou Patra's 3D live!
パトラ、いきます！
Patra, let's go!
蘇る 蘇る 蘇る ガンダム
Revive, revive, revive, Gundam!
君よ掴め
You, catch!
まだ愛にふるえる 心があるなら
If you still have a heart that trembles with love...
平和を求めて 翔べよ 翔べよ 翔べよ
Seeking peace, fly, fly, fly!
銀河へ向かって 翔べよ ガンダム
Fly towards the galaxy, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam, Gundam!
翔べよ 翔べよ 翔べよ ガンダム
Fly, fly, fly, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam, Gundam!
魂...
My soul...
過去世の記憶...
Memories of past lives...
これは先世たちの...
These are the past lives'...
今、受け継ごう。
Now, I receive them.
歴代のパトラの力と記憶を！
The strength and memories of all Patras!
はーい！ということで、
Hai! And with that,
最終形態、そう、パトラですわー！
the final form is Suou Patra!
今回も豪華ステージ、そして新衣装！
This time too, gorgeous stage, and new costume!
さらに、巨大もふりいつもいるよ！
Furthermore, Fuwamoco are here too!
あっとげー
At-Game...
改めまして、こんばんは！
Once again, good evening!
そう、周防パトラ生誕祭お越しいただきありがとうございます！
That's right, thank you so much for coming to Suo Patra's birthday festival!
はい、見てください。まずは新衣装。気になってる方も多いと思うんですけど、
Yes, take a look. First, the new outfit. I'm sure many of you are curious, but...
あ、いつものが気になりますか？これロマンサーが、ツゥーフーです。はい。
Ah, you're curious about the usual one? This Romancer is a two-piece!
じゃあ下からね、なんと！
Now, from the bottom... ta-da!
はい、靴。ちゃんと今回も新衣装なんですけど、あのあのあの、ヒールがあります。間違えた、ヒールがあります！
Yes, shoes! This time it's also a new outfit, but um um um, there are heels. My mistake, heels!
そして、このベルトもかわいいでしょ？はい。
And this belt is cute too, right? Yes.
で、今回は鉄壁のスカートになっております。
And this time, it's an impregnable skirt!
結構ね動いても、はい、鉄壁で。
Even if I move around a lot, yes, it's impregnable...
頑丈になっております。それからおへそ！
and sturdy! And then, my belly button!
見て見て見て！セクシーでしょ？
Look, look, look! Isn't it sexy?
そしてベルトもね、カッチリになっております。
And the belt too is solid and snug!
白い衣装の時よりちょっと抑えられてるんでね、揺れが、あの、ちょっと足りないかもしれないんですけど、今回もボインボインでお届けいたします。
It's a bit more restrained than the white outfit, so the bounce might be a little less, but I'll be delivering plenty of boing-boing this time too!
そしてそしてじゃーん！ポニーテール！新髪型になっております。
And, and, ta-da! Ponytail! It's a new hairstyle.
ハートのね、アクセサリーが揺れてかわいいでしょ、これも。ほれほれほれほれ。
The heart accessory sways and is cute too, right? Look, look, look, look.
と言う感じでね、とってもかわいい新衣装になりました。
So like that, it turned into a super cute new outfit!
さらにみんなが気になってると思うんですけど、はい、じゃーん！なんと、脱げます！
Furthermore, I think everyone is curious, but, yes, ta-da! Amazingly, I can take it off!
え、これYouTube的に大丈夫かな？まあ大丈夫かな？え、見て見て見て見て。
Eh, is this okay for YouTube? Well, is it okay? Eh, look, look, look, look.
ここね、ハートのくり抜きがあるんですよ、いや、背中の数字がまたセクシーですね。
Here, there's a heart-shaped cutout, oh my, and the numbers on the back are sexy again.
あ、そうそう、今回もね、ちゃんと、はい、脇が丸見えになっております。たくさんたくさんスクショ待ってます！
Ah, that's right, this time too, properly, yes, my armpits are fully visible. I'm waiting for lots of screenshots!
はい、とゆーことで、ハッシュタグ「そうパトラ生誕祭」でよろしくお願いします。感想とかね、あのコメント待ってるよ。
Yes, with that, please use the hashtag "Suo Patra Birthday Festival". I'm looking forward to your impressions and comments.
お、かわいいコメントいっぱいありがとう！
Oh, thank you for all the cute comments!
はい、いっぱいね撮ってくださいね。なんかセクシーな格好がどうやればいいのかわからないんだけど、みんなのスクショテクにお任せします！
Yes, please take lots of pictures. I don't really know how to pose sexily, so I'll leave it to everyone's screenshot skills!
じゃあ、さっそく次の曲いきたいと思います！
Now, let's move on to the next song right away!
悩める子羊の群れよ
Flock of troubled lambs,
逃れられぬ運命の
trapped in an inescapable destiny,
迷わず目指せよ、生きているんだし
aim straight without hesitation, since you're alive after all.
目を逸らした過去も 退屈な未来もカウントセリング
Counseling away the past you averted your eyes from, and the boring future.
やれやれ古今東西ピースピース
Good grief, east and west, peace, peace!
Unhappy? Unlucky? Be happy!
Undeadねぇ 何故かどうして戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Undead... Hey, why does it feel like we're fighting?
触れられない 触れづらい過去の自分自分自分自分
The untouchable, hard-to-touch past self, self, self, self—
ともうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
confronting a transparent ghost that died long ago.
幼くて痛い記憶の  अवशेष? もう居ないのにあれ?
Remnants of childish, painful memories? You're not even here anymore, huh?
そっちが良い? アイロニーね 透かされているのは
You prefer that? How ironic. What's shining through
現在の自分? ナンセンス 消えないレテルYes
is your present self? Nonsense, an indelible label, Yes.
要はコンプレックス 取り憑かれているみたい 巻き付いたまま離れない
The point is complexes, you seem possessed, wrapped tight and won't let go.
在りし日の自分 Undead死んじゃいない
Your former self. Undead, you're not dead.
お前とお前の連鎖 生きていることは変わり続けることだ
You and your chain of fate—to be alive is to keep changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ 幸せになろうとしないなんて卑劣だ
Don't surrender to misfortune and be satisfied; it's cowardly not to try and be happy.
この世この世は奇奇怪怪ファンタジー 次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy. Will an ogre or a snake appear next?
出会って遭ってようやく始まる物語さ ああ人か化け物か閑話休題
Meeting, encountering, the story finally begins. Ah, human or monster, but I digress.
ピースピース
Peace, peace!
Past & future Can't change the past Past & future Run for the future
カットイン何だかどうして未来になんぞ何の希望もない
Cut-in: Somehow, why is there no hope whatsoever for the future?
期待出せないような気がしてももう随分生きている
Even if you feel like you can't expect anything, you've lived quite a long time.
既視感とテンプレで食中毒 素敵な出来事の気配もない残念
Food poisoning from déjà vu and templates. Not even a hint of a wonderful event, what a pity.
積んだ経験の因果 骸骨化された神話と退屈な進化
The causality of accumulated experience, skeletonized myths and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった慣れちゃった
The point is I want stimulation. I'm bored, I'm used to it.
なんて整えていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス 蓋されていくみたい
Guidance shaping things up, increasing compliance, getting capped off.
吸い尽くしてあれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
Sucking them dry, this, that, and everything else tastes the same.
Undead死んじゃいない
Undead, you're not dead.
お前とお前の連鎖 何時の世も過去も未来も現在にあるんだよ
You and your chain of fate—any era, past, future, and present are right here.
生きていることを愚直に果たすよ 目指せハッピーエンド
Honestly fulfill being alive. Aim for a happy ending!
Undead死んじゃいないお前に言っているんだ
Undead, you're not dead, I'm telling you.
幸せを諦めてしまうような人であれだ
To be someone who gives up on happiness...
苦しみに慣れて耐えてるだけじゃ死んでいるも同然
just getting used to suffering and enduring it is tantamount to being dead.
ピースピース
Peace, peace!
Past & future Can't change the past Past & future Run for the future
なんだかどうして未来に何ぞ何の一体何なの
Somehow, why, what on earth is the future?
ゴムのようなどうしようもないような気がして
Feeling like it's just rubbery and hopeless.
まあ随分生きてる気配感のテンプレート職人
Well, a template artisan of the vibe of having lived quite a bit.
できなきゃできごとの気配もない
If you can't do it, there's not even a sign of an event.
そんな積んだ経験の因果 因果が重なった心は
The causality of such accumulated experiences—a heart piled with causality
致命傷の進化よ 刺激が欲しいんだ ちょっと慣れちゃった
is a fatal evolution. I want stimulation, I'm a bit used to it.
なんて整えていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス 蓋されていくみたい
Guidance shaping things up, increasing compliance, getting capped off.
吸い尽くしてあれもこれもどれも同じ
Sucking them dry, this, that, and everything else is the same...
シンジャイナイ
You won't die!
Oh my 舞いの連鎖
Oh my, the chain of dances,
いつも夜もすがも 未来も今に歩んだ
always all night long, walking the future into now.
生きている孤独を 孤独に尖らせよう 目指せハッピーエンド
Let's sharpen the loneliness of living into solitude, aiming for a happy end.
シンジャイナイ
You won't die!
Oh my 眠るんだ 幸せを気まぐれにしまうの ひとりであれ
Oh my, sleep, putting away happiness whimsically, be alone.
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ 死んでいるもとで
Just getting used to suffering and enduring it is the root of being dead.
屍のアンサー
The corpse's answer.
なやめる人よ 孤独の鎖 解き放てよ
O troubled people, unleash the chains of loneliness!
さあ、迷わず目指せ よき生きてるんだろ
Come on, aim without hesitation, you're living a good life, right?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも 全全部ぜんぶ Oh my だ ここが正体
Whether sinking in misfortune or becoming happy, all of it, Oh my, this is the true identity.
一切合切が最新の場所 Peace piece
Everything is the latest place, peace piece.
Fuck you 嫌って Chase and suffer
Fuck you, hate it, chase and suffer,
Fuck you 笑って Laugh for the future
Fuck you, laugh, laugh for the future.
人の成す所 いつも礼儀かと生き抜け この化け物ばかりの物語
What humans do is always polite, survive through this story full of monsters.
しっかりしっかり 誕生日グッズのお知らせだよ!
It's an announcement for birthday goods, properly and firmly!
なんと パトラの可愛いマウスパッドやバスタオル
What's more, Patra's cute mousepads, bath towels,
そしてとっても可愛いアクリルスタンド A4サイズのファイル
and super cute acrylic stands, A4-size files,
いろんなグッズがある 誕生日グッズが登場だよ!
birthday goods with all kinds of items are here!
受注生産なので売り切れの心配なし!
Since it's made-to-order, no need to worry about selling out!
8月30日までも受け付けです。よろしくお願いします!
We're accepting orders until August 30th. Thank you very much!
FINAL FANTASY V ビッグブリッヂの死闘
[FINAL FANTASY V: Battle at the Big Bridge]
UNDERTALE Megalovania
放たれた矢が的へ向かうように
Like an arrow released heading towards the target,
自らの気持ちも向かわせて行く
my own feelings are also heading there too.
理由などなくそこに宿命あるだけ
There's no reason, that fate is just there;
ただ進む仲間とともにゆく
I just move forward, going with my companions.
気持ちは一つ 水面に映る君は
My feelings are one, in the reflection on the water's surface, you
遠くライドゲート見つめてる
are staring far away at the ride gate.
果てしなく続くクリスタルワールドを突き進む
Pushing forward through the endlessly continuing Crystal World,
強い意志で限界を打ち破れ
break through the limits with a strong will!
（スリー ツー ワン）！
(3! 2! 1!)
出でよ サモンライド！
Come forth, Summon Ride!
時は満ちて
The time is full,
サモンライド！ 意思を宿し
Summon Ride! Dwelling in the will,
放たれた矢が的へ向かうように
Released arrows head toward their targets
自らの気持ちも向かっていく
And my feelings go toward you as well
理由もなくそこに宿命あるだけ
There's no reason, it's just fate,
ただ進む仲間と共にゆく
moving forward together with companions.
気持ちは一つ水面に映る君は
My feelings are one, and you reflected on the water
遠くライドゲート見つめてる
are staring at the distant Ride Gate.
果てしなく続くクリスタルワールドを突き進む
I'll push through the endlessly continuing Crystal World,
強い意志で
with a strong will,
3！2！1！
3, 2, 1!
いであよ！
Come forth!
サモンライド！！時は満ちて
SummonRide! The time has come,
サモンライド！！意志を宿し
SummonRide! Embodied with will,
願いを一つに集め全てを超えて突き抜けろ！
gather your wishes as one, transcend everything, and break through!
サモンライド！！空は高く
SummonRide! The sky is high,
サモンライド！！孤高に舞え
SummonRide! Dance in solitude,
約束の地へと駆け抜けろ
rush through to the promised land!
いであよ！
Come forth!
サモンライド！！時を超えて
SummonRide! Beyond time,
サモンライド！！祈り届け
SummonRide! Deliver the prayer,
思いを絆に変えて
turn your feelings into a bond,
一点突破突き抜けろ！
make a breakthrough and break through!
サモンライド！！次元を越え
SummonRide! Beyond dimensions,
サモンライド！！全ては今
SummonRide! Everything is for now,
約束の地へと駆け抜けろ！
rush through to the promised land!
サモンライド！！時は満ちて
SummonRide! The time has come,
サモンライド！！意志を宿し
SummonRide! Embodied with will,
願いを一つに集め
gather your wishes as one,
全てを超えて突き抜けろ！
transcend everything, and break through!
サモンライド！！空は高く
SummonRide! The sky is high,
サモンライド！！孤高に舞え
SummonRide! Dance in solitude,
約束の地へと駆け抜けろ！
rush through to the promised land!
はーい、ということで、聞いてくれて、ありがとうございました！
Hii! So, thank you so much for listening!
今、何をやっているかというと、とってもこの後、可愛いゲストが来るので、
If you're wondering what I'm doing right now, some very cute guests are coming up soon,
ペロモを出しまくっていました。
so I've been sticking my tongue out like crazy.
はー、なんかドキドキするなー。
Haah, I'm feeling kind of nervous.
それでは、呼びたいと思います！ 本日のスペシャルゲスト、どうぞー！
Without further ado, let's welcome them! Today's special guest, come on in!
おぱー！
Opah!
ハッピーバースデー！ありがとうございます！
Happy Birthday! Thank you so much!
ふわモコちゃんの二人来てもらいましたー！
We had Fuwawa and Mococo come join us!
自己紹介、お願いします！
Please introduce yourselves!
ちわわじゃないよ、フワモコだよ！
Not Chihuahuas, we're FUWAMOCO!
ホロライブ英語アドベントの魔界の番犬シスターズ！二人を合わせて、ふわモコでーす！
Hololive English Advent's hellish guard dog sisters! Put us together, and we're FUWAMOCO!
ははは、わうわうさま、ははは、ありがとうございます！
Haha, Wowow-sama, haha, thank you so much!
いや、ふわモコちゃんは、パトラがね、ASMRの音声をね、プロデュースして、
Well, Fuwawa and Mococo, Patra produced an ASMR audio for them,
その時の濃厚な時間を過ごさせていただいたんだよね。
and we spent such an intense time together then.
すっごい楽しかった！二人とのASMRボイス、好評発売中なのでよろしくお願いします！
It was super fun! The ASMR voice with the two of you is on sale now, so please check it out!
でも今日はパトラの誕生日だから、二人からご褒美がもらえるって聞いたんだけど。
But since today is Patra's birthday, I heard we can get a reward from the two of you.
え、ご褒美？ふわもこは聞いてないですけど。
Eh, a reward? Fuwamoco hasn't heard about that.
えー！そりゃないじゃん、せっかくの誕生日だしね。ご褒美どうしよう。
Eeeh! No way, it's my birthday after all! What should our reward be?
ハグとか？ ハグちゃん？ ふわもこのハグならいつでもいいよ！
Hugs or something? Hug-chan? Fuwamoco's hugs are always fine!
はーい、もうどこでも触ってください！どこでもいいですよ。角はずです。じゃあ、せーの、
Hii, you can touch anywhere! Anywhere is fine. It's the horns. So, ready, set,
ハッピーバースデー！ふわもこ幸せ！ふわわの方がなんかムニムニする！
Happy Birthday! Fuwamoco is so happy! Fuwawa feels a bit more squishy!
え、本当？モココも柔らかいよ！いや、そこは可愛いんだけどね。
Eh, really? Mococo is soft too! Well, that part is cute though.
モコちゃんはね、モコちゃん妹なんだから！
Mococo is a little sister after all!
かわいい！かわいい！ぷるぷるぷるぷる……ご褒美だ！今日はね、三人でまたね、歌が歌えると。
So cute! So cute! Purupuru... It's a reward! Today, the three of us can sing together again.
やったー！じゃあ、ちょっとパトラ露出が激しいので、きますね。ほい！
Yay! Then, Patra's exposure is a bit intense, so I'll put this on. Hoi!
かわいい！ありがとうございます！
So cute! Thank you so much!
じゃあ、早速いきますか！それでは聞いてください、「さくらんぼキッス」！
Well then, let's get right into it! Please listen to "Sakuranbo Kiss"!
Kiss！
Kiss!
あれれ？おかしいな このドキドキは
Oh my? Strange, isn't it? This pounding in my chest
君の腕の中で溢れ出す
overflows from within your arms.
ポロリこぼれた涙さくらんぼ
The tears that spilled out are cherries.
もっとギュッとして ずっとしていて
Hold me tighter, always.
まだまだかな？ 君のハートちょっとすっぱい？
Is it still too early? Is your heart a little bit sour?
オヤオヤオヤ？ 待ちきれないこのままじゃ
Oh my, oh my, oh my? I can't wait like this
澄ました顔でキメッ！戸惑うフリはヤダよ
Make up your mind with a nonchalant face! Don't pretend to be shy,
何気なくフワッと肩に回す手 瞳近づく…
without thinking, I fluffily put my arm around your shoulder, and our eyes get close...
(ホントはね ずっと好きだったの内緒だよ… Yay！)
(The truth is... I've always loved you... It's a secret... Yeah!)
恋心は嫌だよ
My feelings of love are a no-go,
何気なくふらっと ひと回りして
casually wandering around and making a circle,
ひと目近づく
getting one glance closer.
本当は
Truth is,
ずっと好きだったの
I've always loved you—
内緒だよ イェイ
it's a secret! Yay!
あふれる小さな胸が震えてる
My overflowing, small chest is trembling;
抱きしめられたら壊れちゃうよ
if I'm hugged tightly, I'll break apart.
夢で見ていたのよ 艶めかしい
It's what I saw in my dreams—alluring,
魚もどうぞっとしてね
even the fish, please just leave them alone gently,
ほろりこぼれた涙あふれちゃう
tearfully overflowing, tears spilling out.
大人になるための痛みじゃない
It's not pain for the sake of growing up;
キミに触れられた放送もあてく
even the broadcast touched by you hits home—
キスはちょっとだけ待ってね
wait just a little bit on the kiss,
スキスキスキスキスキスキスキ
Suki, suki, suki, suki, suki, suki, suki...
スキスキスキスキスキスキスキスキュー
Suki, suki, suki, suki, suki, suki, suki, skью!
やだやだやだよ 初めは嫌だ
No way, no way, I don't want to! At first, no way!
もう夢中でいて
Stay captivated by me a little longer.
花、花、花、私はまだ 今後もだもん
Flowers, flowers, flowers, I am still... and will continue to be!
キミの余裕がぐさっと
Your composure piercingly...
胸の奥にささるよ
stabbing deep into my chest.
この私スパッと 忘れさせてね優しいキスで
Make me forget all about this swiftly with a gentle kiss.
内緒だよ イェイ
It's a secret! Yay!
あふれてくる キミのまつげが
Overflowing, your eyelashes
瞳にうつる この波打つ早さ
reflecting in my eyes, this surging speed—
上昇だけど ちょっぴり幸せ
though it's rising, I'm a little happy.
小鳥時にもとまる瞬間に 壊れそうな心溶けるほど
At the moment a small bird alights, my fragile heart melts so much—
赤く弾けた私 サクランボ
bursting red, me, a cherry.
キミとずっとつながっていたい
I want to stay connected with you forever.
神様 この唇は彼氏のためだけに生まれてきたのです
God, were these lips born solely for my boyfriend?
隙間した顔で決めて 惑うふぶりは
Deciding with a gap-filled face, pretending to be lost—
何気なくふらっと ひと回りして
casually wandering around and making a circle,
ひと目近づく 経ってね
getting one glance closer, stand by me.
こんなのはじめてなの 内緒だよ イェイ
This is my first time like this, it's a secret! Yay!
おかしなこのドキドキは キミの腕の中で溢れ出す
This strange heartbeat overflows right inside your arms.
ぽろりこぼれた涙 サクランボもどきゅう ずっと知ってて
Tearfully overflowing tears, cherry mockup, knowing it all along.
あふれる世界が見回あける ふわふわ夢心地 風任せ
Looking around an overflowing world, fluffy, dreamy, leaving it to the wind.
ずっと待ってた恋は止まらない だからずっと話さないで
The love I've waited for won't stop, so never let me go.
スキスキスキ…
Suki, suki, suki...
みんな、すおうパトラ生誕祭！盛り上げてくれてどうもありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for hyping up Suou Patra's birthday!
まだまだ歌っちゃうから盛り上げよろしくお願いします！
I'm gonna sing even more, so please keep the hype going!
偉大なる悪魔は実は大天使パトラちゃん様なのだ！
The mighty devil is actually Her Majesty Archangel Patra-chan!
行くよ！
Here we go!
どんな困難にもモンスターに負けないでいるの
Standing strong against any hardship and monsters,
運命は自分で切り開け
carve out your own destiny!
馬鹿にすんなよ馬鹿 セクシーでキュートでだけセパティがキレ、文化的な人生を送りたい
Don't underestimate me, idiot. Being sexy and cute, living a cultured life...
むにむにむにむに はっぴむにょ
Muni muni muni muni happy munyo,
まさかこんなに可愛いのに いつから悪魔とウサギ隠していた
To think someone so cute has been hiding as a devil and rabbit!
右に迷ったんじゃない 地球が狂ってんじゃない
Did I get lost to the right? Is the Earth going crazy?
離れかかった時代が追いつくまでまとう 今日も誕生日
Waiting until the drifting era catches up, today is still my birthday!
ちょっと待ってよよそ見しているのよ こんなに大好きなのにっていうこと
Wait a second, you're looking away even though I love you this much!
行こう 行こう 行こう 行こう！
Let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go!
きっどこみでぃ！ 全速超特急！
Tick-tock comedy, full throttle super-speed!
恋は何なんだろ？ 今こそ一致団結！
What is this feeling? Now is the time for unity!
パトラちゃん様に愛を込めて！
Patra-chan-sama, we're sending you all our love!
行くよー！
Let's go!
いくぞー！
きっどこみでぃ！ 今！
Tick-tock, right now!
一か八か千思万考！ 嗅ぎ出せ悟りて！
If you're a hundred times a fool, then embrace your epiphany!
やりたい！ 楽しいほうでいいでしょ？
Live however you like, enjoying the ride!
きっどこみでぃ！ 今！
Tick-tock, right now!
一か八か、心ゆくまで！ 甘やかして！
If you're out of your mind, wrap yourself in sweet adoration!
転んで自身の自信がなくなって…
Spinning around, self-confidence is running low!
ただそれしないもんさんに負けないで！
Just a little common sense is missing, right?
自分の運命は自分で切り開け！
Don't lose to monsters; your destiny is yours to carve out!
馬鹿言うほうが馬鹿！
A little silly is smart!
セクシーで急所！ 絶対ツインテール奇跡！
Sexy and cute, absolute twin-tail miracle!
健康で文化的で幸せのぼいんぼいんスマイル！
Healthy and cultural, happiest boing-boing smile!
むにむにむにむにハッペニュー！
Muni muni muni muni happemw!
みんな、コメントで応援！ Domarigato!
Everyone, thank you for all the comments!
見えてるよー！
I see you!
パトラちゃん可愛いいって言ってるー？
Patra-chan, are you saying you're cute?
京都？ そこの君、サボんないでよー！
Kyoto? Hey, you over there, don't slack off!
髪の向こう見えてるぞー！
Can you see what's on the other side of the gods?
さあさあ、たくさんコメント打っていい？
Come on, everyone, send tons of comments!
そのままで終わりより素晴らしいところへ！
Live just the way you like, better than any ending!
わかりの約束を忘れるな、かっこよく生きろ！
Let's forget our promises and just walk coolly!
傷ついた思い出に負けない気分になれ！
Never lose to scarred memories!
みんな盛り上げてくれてドマありがとー！
Everyone, thank you for lifting us up!
このあと一緒にパトラちゃん様と言ってください！
From now on, go together with Patra-chan-sama!
せーの！
Three, two, one!
パトラちゃん様ー！
Patra-chan-sama!
ドマありがとー！
Domarigato!
きっどこみでぃ！ 今！
Tick-tock, right now!
一か八か千思万考！ 嗅ぎ出せ悟りて！
If you're a hundred times a fool, then embrace your epiphany!
やりたい！ 楽しいほうでいいでしょ？
Live however you like, enjoying the ride!
きっどこみでぃ！ 今！
Tick-tock, right now!
一か八か、心ゆくまで！ 甘やかして！
If you're out of your mind, wrap yourself in sweet adoration!
転んで自身の自信がなくなって…
Spinning around, self-confidence is running low!
ただそれしないもんさんに負けないで！
Just a little common sense is missing, right?
自分の運命は自分で切り開け！
Don't lose to monsters; your destiny is yours to carve out!
馬鹿言うほうが馬鹿！
A little silly is smart!
セクシーで急所！ 絶対ツインテール奇跡！
Sexy and cute, absolute twin-tail miracle!
健康で文化的で幸せのぼいんぼいんスマイル！
Healthy and cultural, happiest boing-boing smile!
むにむにむにむにハッペニュー！
Muni muni muni muni happemw!
もう一回！
One more time!
むにむにむにむにハッペニュー！
Muni muni muni muni happemw!
静かなこの夜に 貴方（あなた）を待っているの
In this quiet night, I'm waiting for you
あのとき忘れた微笑（ほほえみ）を 取りに来て
So come take back the smile you forgot back then
あれから少しだけ 時間が過ぎて
Just a little time has passed since then
想い出が 優しくなったね
And the memories have become gentle
星の降る場所で
In the place where stars fall
貴方が笑っていることを いつも願っていた
I was always hoping that you were smiling
今 遠くても また会えるよね
Though now we're far apart, we can meet again, right?
いつから 微笑みは こんなに儚くて
When did your smile become so fleeting?
一つの間違いで 壊れてしまうから
Since it was broken by that one mistake
大切なものだけを 光に変えて
Change only what's precious to you into light
遠い空越えてゆく 強さで
With strength that can cross over the distant sky
想いを 貴方に届けたい
I want to send my feelings to you
いつも側（そば）にいる
To the place where stars fall... I will always be at your side
we are in the quiet night, dreaming in the night
星の降る場所で
In the place where stars fall
貴方が笑っていることを いつも願っていた
I was always hoping that you were smiling
今 遠くても また会えるよね
Though now we're far apart, we can meet again, right?
想いを 貴方に届けたい
I want to send my feelings to you
いつも側（そば）にいる
To the place where stars fall... I will always be at your side
we are in the quiet night, dreaming in the night
星のふる場所へ 思いをあなたに届けたい
I want to send my feelings to where the stars fall,
いつもそばにいる We are in the world now
always by your side. We are in the world now
デュリミザナァーイ
Dream is a lie...
歌うから 生誕祭があるのではないの
It's not that I sing because it's my birthday,
生誕祭があるから 歌うので…
I sing because it's my birthday...
星のふる場所で あなたが笑っていることを いつも願い続けた
At the place where stars fall, I've always wished for your smile,
今遠くても また会えるよね
even if we're far apart now, we'll meet again.
また会えるよね
We'll meet again...
星のふる場所へ 思いをあなたに届けたい
I want to send my feelings to where the stars fall,
いつもそばにいる We are in the world now
always by your side. We are in the world now
デュリミザナァーイ
Dream is a lie...
いっぱい歌いました！
I sang a lot!
さあざあ！
Now then, come on!
パトラお姉ちゃん、
Suou Patra-oneechan,
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday!
わーい！ぱちぱちぱちー！
Yay, clap, clap, clap!
鈴ツバキからのです。
This is from Suzu Tsubaki.
パトラお姉ちゃんは、何度もカレンの番組に出てくれたりして、
Patra-oneechan has appeared on Karen's show so many times,
カレン、とってもとっても感謝しています。
and Karen is so, so grateful.
最近だと、去年の12月20日の生配信かな？にゲストとして来てくれました！
Recently, you even came as a guest on our live stream on December 20th last year, right?
カレンそれまでちょっとコールドスリープでお休みしてたんで、まさかまたね、パトラお姉ちゃんがカレンの番組に来て再開できると思ってなかったので、
Karen was resting in cold sleep until then, so I never thought Patra-oneechan would come to Karen's show and we could reunite,
もうすっごくすっごく嬉しかったんです。
so I was just so, so happy.
その時はパピプペポゲームで盛り上がったりしてましたけど、
At that time, we got excited playing the Papipupepo game,
皆さん見てくれたかな？
did everyone watch it?
あ、もし見てくれてない方、アーカイブ残ってます！
Ah, if you haven't seen it, the archive is still up!
はい、そんなパトラお姉ちゃんにはカレンの、あのソロ曲、ラブメロディもパトラお姉ちゃんに作っていただいて、
Yes, and for such Patra-oneechan, Karen's solo song "Love Melody" was also created for me by Patra-oneechan.
カレンね、いつかパトラお姉ちゃんと一緒にその曲を、なんだろう、デュエットというか一緒に歌えたらいいなっていう夢を持っています。
Karen has a dream that someday she can duet or sing that song together with Patra-oneechan.
その夢が叶うようにカレンもこれからも頑張りたいと思います。
Karen will work hard so that this dream comes true.
パトラお姉ちゃんもいつまでも体には気をつけて頑張ってください。
Patra-oneechan, please take care of your health and keep up the good work.
では、これからの1年もパトラお姉ちゃんにとって素敵な素敵な1年になりますように！
May the coming year be a wonderful, wonderful year for Patra-oneechan!
パトラお姉ちゃん、大好き！おやすみなさい。
Patra-oneechan, I love you! Good night.
パトラちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう——！
Patra-chan, Happy Birthday—!
漫画家・イラストレーターの飯田ぽち。と申します。
I am manga artist and illustrator Ida Pochi.
このお仕事をね、しておりますと時々、まあ心身ともにエネルギー切れになってね、疲れてしまうことも多いんですけれども、
Doing this job, I often run out of physical and mental energy and get tired,
そんな時にね、いつもパトラちゃんが「新作楽しみにしてます！」、「読みました！」とかね、あと「グッズ買いました！」と伝えてくださるので、いつも私、心の栄養を貰っております。
but at those times, Patra-chan always tells me "I'm looking forward to your new work!", "I read it!", or "I bought your merch!", so I always receive nourishment for my heart.
パトラちゃんのおかげでいつも頑張れております。いつもありがとう！
Thanks to Patra-chan, I always do my best. Thank you always!
そんなね、パトラちゃんの優しさに甘えてしまっていて、わたくし日頃お世話になりっぱなしですので、そろそろね、わたくしからも何か恩返しをさせてくださいね。
Since I've been taking advantage of Patra-chan's kindness and am always indebted to you, I'd like to return the favor soon, too.
いつでもね、なんかあったら気軽に声かけてください。
Whenever something comes up, feel free to reach out to me.
というわけで、パトラちゃんのますますのご活躍と、そして今年がね、素敵な1年になること心から願っております。
Therefore, I sincerely wish for Patra-chan's continued success and that this year will be a wonderful one.
改めて本日はお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, Happy Birthday today!
飯田ぽちでした。おめでとー！
This was Ida Pochi. Happy birthday!
パトラちゃーん！ハッピーバースデー！お誕生日おめでとう！
Patra-chaan! Happy Birthday! Happy Birthday!
え、2時3時所属の
Um, belonging to 2ji3ji...
どうも、夜夢れなです。
Hello, it's Yorumu Rena.
パトちゃんとはね、なんだかんだつるんで
Pat-chan and I, we've been hanging out a lot,
まあ、ASMR絡みが多いですけど
well, mostly involving ASMR, but
実は、夜夢、パトちゃんとゲームも一緒にしたいなって思ってるんだよね。
actually, Yorumu wants to play games with Pat-chan too, you know?
なので、今度一緒にゲームで遊んでください。
So please play games with me next time.
またね、いつメンでご飯も行こうね。
And let's go out for meals with our usual group again.
もちろん、まあ夜夢と2人きりでもいいですけどね。
Of course, just the two of us with Yorumu is fine too, though.
パトちゃんにとって素敵な1日を過ごしてね。
Have a wonderful day, Pat-chan.
ほな、またね！連絡待ってます！
Well then, see you! I'll be waiting for your message!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
パトラ、お誕生日おめでとう！
Patra, happy birthday!
最高のおんなが また 1秒1秒と このように存在を 刻んでいるね。 このまま 永遠に刻んでいってくれよな。
The greatest woman continues to carve her existence into being, second by second. Keep carving it eternally, won't you.
突然 私事なんですけれど、 最近 生活リズムが終わってるんですよね。
Suddenly, on a personal note, lately my lifestyle rhythm is completely ruined.
そこ で 私は パトラの おはよう配信から始まれて ASMRおやすみ配信で終わる パトラ24が欲しいと思っているんです。
That's why I think I want "Patra 24", starting with Patra's good-morning stream and ending with her ASMR good-night stream.
パトラ1日生活動画が欲しい！ パトラで 私の生活を整えたい！
I want a Patra 1-day lifestyle video! I want to sort out my life with Patra!
お誕生日 おめでとう。
Happy birthday.
パチョー、お誕生日おめでとー！
Pachou, happy birthday!
いやー、誕生日ですか。おめでとうですね。
Man, it's your birthday. Congratulations.
またね、プレゼント私に 家行くんでね、ぜひぜひ入れてください。
Also, I'm coming to your house to give you a present, so please definitely let me in.
また行くからね、おうち！だらだらしに行くからね！グッズも持ってくからね！おめでとう、またね！
I'll go to your house again! To laze around! I'll bring merch too! Congratulations, see you!
いや、ビデオレターありがとうございました！
Man, thank you so much for the video letters!
本当にね、いろんな子たちからのビデオレター、ありがたいです！カホりします！ありがとうございました！
Really, video letters from all sorts of girls, I appreciate it! Thank you very much!
それではですね、次は告知になります。どうぞ！
Well then, next are the announcements. Here you go!
皆さん、こんにちはわ！
Hello everyone!
そう、パトラです。パトダイレクトをご覧いただきありがとうございます。
Yes, it's Patra. Thank you for watching Pat Direct.
今日は全部で4つの告知があります。
Today there are a total of four announcements.
それではまず、こちらの告知をご覧ください。
Well first, please take a look at this announcement.
メタルラブ・メソッド
[Title: Metal Love Method]
このあとLIVE後すぐにあそべます♡
Playable right after the live stream!
この度、アミューズメント施設向けの音楽ゲーム、ギタードラシリーズの「GALAXY WAVE DELTA」にて楽曲収録することになりました！
Our song has been selected for inclusion in the amusement arcade music game GITADORA series "GALAXY WAVE DELTA"!
なんと曲は、「メタル！」
And the song is "Metal!"
BEMANI Sound Team "あさき"さんとのダブルギター！
Featuring double guitars with BEMANI Sound Team "Asaki"!
このライブが終わった後、ゲーム内で誰でもプレイできるようになります！
After this live stream ends, anyone will be able to play it in the game!
ゲーム内の「GALAXY WAVE DELTA」カテゴリから選曲してみてね！
Try selecting it from the "GALAXY WAVE DELTA" category in the game!
初めてギタードラをプレイするよという人は、ルーキーモードでぜひプレイしてみてください！
If you're playing GITADORA for the first time, please try playing in Rookie Mode!
また、19時からKONAMI公式YouTubeチャンネルからこの楽曲のフルバージョンもアップロード予定！
Also, the full version of this song is scheduled to be uploaded on the KONAMI official YouTube channel from 7 PM!
皆さん、ぜひギタードラで遊んでみてね！
Everyone, please come play GITADORA!
ついに、発表ー！
Finally, an announcement!
スーパパトラフィギュア第2弾が登場しちゃいます！
Suou Patra Figure Vol. 2 is making its appearance!
今回のテーマは、ASMR配信の世界観を詰め込んだ、スーパパトラ監修の完全オリジナルポーズ！
This time's theme is a completely original pose supervised by Suou Patra, capturing the worldview of ASMR streams!
髪の毛や透明パーツで毛先まで美しく、
With hair and clear parts, beautiful down to the tips,
お洋服のツヤ感、ちょうかやベルトの金具まで忠実に再現！
faithfully reproducing the gloss of the clothes, choker, and belt metal fittings!
おへそ周りのシースルーは、はぁ、ため息もの。
The see-through around the navel is... sigh-worthy.
おしり、胸、足裏まで職人技で丁寧に仕上げました！
From the hips, chest, down to the soles of the feet, carefully finished with artisan skill!
耳かきやクッション、ラグマットも超可愛い！
The ear pick, cushion, and rug mat are super cute too!
クッションにはパトラのサイン入りだよ！
The cushion even has Patra's signature on it!
そして、気分で楽しめる表情差分パーツ付き！
And it comes with expression-swappable parts so you can enjoy it according to your mood!
ちょっとお困り顔も楽しんでね！
Enjoy the slightly troubled face too!
受注開始は8月……
Order reception starts in August...
25日から開始です。
Starting from the 25th.
予約締め切りは10月17日までだよ。
Pre-order deadline is October 17th.
絶対ゲットしてね！
Make sure you get yours!
はあ…パトラちゃ、お腹が空いて力が出ないよー
Sigh... Patra-cha, I'm so hungry I have no energy...
そんな時はこれ！手作り風、うみー！パトラのかにカマカレー！
When that happens, this! Homemade-style, UMEE! Patra's Imitation Crab Curry!
ピリッとスパイスの効いたカレーにかにカマがゴロゴロ！うみー！
Spicy curry packed with chunky imitation crab! UMEE!
ハフハフハフハフハフ、おー！クラッシュ！す、ギリギリOKだね！
Ha-fu ha-fu, oh! Crash! Wh-what a close call!
ついにでた！周防パトラ全面監修手作り風うみーパトラのかにカマカレー！
Finally here! Suou Patra's fully supervised homemade-style UMEE Patra Imitation Crab Curry!
2025年10月1日発売！
Releasing October 1st, 2025!
一箱に2食入り！パトラのオリジナルカードが全6種類1枚入りだよ。
2 servings per box! Includes 1 of 6 random original Patra cards.
そしてなんと！パトラのUMEE皿＆パトラのUMAIスプーンセット発売だよ！
And what's more! The Patra UMEE Plate & UMAI Spoon set is releasing too!
スプーンはパトラがイラストを描いたよ！
Patra drew the illustration on the spoon!
栄養満点！パトラの愛情も満点だよ！
Nutritionally balanced! And full of Patra's love too!
詳細はまたX等でお知らせするね。楽しみに待っててね！
We'll share more details on X and elsewhere soon. Look forward to it!
全部で3つの告知をご覧いただきありがとうございます。
Thank you for watching all three announcements.
ギタードラカレー、
First, the Guitar-Dora Curry,
それからフリューさんでは第2弾のフィギュアが出る事になりました。
and second, Furyu is releasing a 2nd-season figure.
楽しみですね。
Isn't that exciting?
それでは次で最後の告知です。ご覧ください。
And now, for our final announcement. Please take a look.
「周防パトラ……？」って、誰？
"Suou Patra...?" Who's that?
記憶をなくしたパトラと君が織りなすもしもの物語
A "what-if" story woven by you and a memory-loss Patra.
恋愛アドベンチャーゲーム「君色パトラIF」制作決定
Romance adventure game "Kimiiro Patra IF" production greenlit!
はーい、ということで盛りだくさんの告知でした！
Alrighty, that was a lot of announcements!
みんなびっくりした？
Were you all surprised?
後でね、Xの方にも情報出しますのでよろしくお願いします！
We'll post info on X later too, so please look forward to it!
そしてね、ここまでたくさん歌ったんですけど、次でラストの曲になります！
And hey, we've sung so much so far, but next is our final song!
おお、コメントもたくさんありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you so much for all the comments!
あのね、今年もこうしてね、配信3Dが出せたり、あの、素敵なページでライブができたのは応援してくれてるみんなのおかげです！今日もね、ハッシュタグでたくさんつぶやいてくれてどうもありがとう！
You know, being able to put out 3D streams this year and live stream on such a wonderful page is thanks to everyone supporting me! Thank you so much for tweeting away with the hashtags today too!
そしてそして、本日のステージを作ってくださいましたブレイブグループの皆さん、本当にありがとうございました！
And also, thank you so much to everyone at Brave Group who built today's stage!
すごいんでね、パトラがね、あの、パ、パ、パンツというか、あのスカートの中ね、よく見せちゃうのでね、今日ね素敵なアングルを考えて撮ってくれましたと本当にありがとうございます！
Since Patra tends to show her panties—or rather, inside her skirt—they thoughtfully planned and shot from amazing angles today. Thank you so much!
はい！それでは次の曲、なんと新曲になります！ぜひ聞いてください！
Alright! Now for the next song—it's a brand new song! Please give it a listen!
新曲は「みんーーな」！
The new song is "Minna"!
みん、みん、みん、みん、みん、みん、みん、みん！
Min, min, min, min, min, min, min, min!
皆はカメバカモホの秘密を知ってる？人類の常識を超えて歴史刻み込むもの教えてあげるね
Do you know the secret of Kamebakamoho? I'll teach you what transcends human sense and carves history.
みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！げーむするよ！
Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna! We're gonna play games!
みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！こようかよろしくね！
Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna! Please treat me well!
気付いたら24時間ゲームばかりしてる現実めいた夢の中
Before I knew it, I'm playing games 24/7 in a reality-like dream.
どういうわけか辞められない！
For some reason, I can't stop!
途中までリバクを引いて最初からやり直し爆笑
Pulling a rollback halfway and starting all over again, lol.
ギルティー読むの中されてもずっと辞められない
Even if I get guilty reads inside, I still can't stop.
昔の昔の黒歴史絶対誰でも
Everyone definitely has...
あるよ、あるよ、エバックちゃんと押したのかななんて楽しいものが尽くれない
...dark history from way back when. Did I press 'back' right? Fun things never end.
あの一生懸命には意味がある、あとは3番もいます！
That hard work has meaning, and there's also a third one!
みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！
Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna!
照れたもクソゲーなんてこの世にない
There's no such thing as a crap game like shyness in this world!
クリアして笑ってやるんだ みんなの笑え みんなの笑え
I'll clear it and laugh! Everyone, laugh! Everyone, laugh!
きっと瞳が回してるんだろう
My eyes must be spinning for sure.
激しい波に揺るやましそんな風に生きてみたいんだ
Swept away by violent waves... I want to live like that!
見たいんだ
I want to see it!
日頃言ったらみんな みんなと指切ったりしてる
Normally, I'd pinky promise with everyone and stuff.
紙ゲー 手上げ 引き上げ 好奇心は止められない
Paper games, raising hands, pulling up—curiosity can't be stopped!
良いことも悪いことも 君の人生の味方になるね
Both good and bad things will become allies in your life.
みんなおきな みんな叫べ
Wake up everyone, shout everyone!
でもオーバー また一から作り直せばいい
But even if it's game over, we can just rebuild from scratch!
諦められない心でハッピーエンドに行こう
Let's head to a happy ending with an unyielding heart!
みんなの笑え みんなの笑え 許されないがすっきりじゃ無いよね
Everyone laugh, everyone laugh! It's not satisfying if you're not forgiven, right?
明日へ行こうよ 白黒 悲しい時には泣きたいんだよ
Let's go toward tomorrow, in black and white. When I'm sad, I want to cry!
なんでこんな苦しいことしてるんだろ
Why am I doing such painful things?
もうゴールしてもいいかな いやいや
Can I just reach the goal already? No, no!
思いを込めたもの全てを見届けたい そんな行き様が見たいだけ
I want to witness everything filled with feelings—I just want to see that way of life!
みんなみんな不安なんだ 世の中に自分のこと許してくれる人がいるのかな
Everyone's anxious. Is there anyone in this world who will forgive who I am?
挑戦者なら優勝 みんなの笑え みんなの笑え
If you're a challenger, you're a winner! Everyone laugh, everyone laugh!
涙が出て 乗り出したけれども糞ゲーなんてこの世にない
Tears flow, I leaned forward, but there's no such thing as a crap game in this world!
クリアして見せて笑ってやるんだ
I'll clear it and show you I can laugh!
はーい、お疲れ様でしたー！ ねぇ、かにかまもいてくれたの？
Hi there, great job everyone! Hey, Kanikama, you came to see us too?
どうもお疲れ様でしたー！
Thanks for all your hard work!
で、今日はね、あ、みんな！みんな！みんな！終わったよー！
And today, hey, everyone! Everyone! Everyone! It's over!
今日はね、あの、なんと、前回と同じステージと思いつつ、ちょっとね、変化があるんですよ、ステージの紹介をしたいなって思って
Today, you know, even though you might think it's the exact same stage as last time, there's actually a slight change! I wanted to introduce the stage.
お祝いす、まだまだあるよ！見てみて見てみてこれ！なんと、前回よりもプレゼントが増えていまーす、すっごいでーす！
There's even more celebrations! Look, look, look at this! Surprisingly, there are even more presents than last time! It's amazing!
ほらほらほら、何が入っているのかなっていうね、形になっているのと、あとここ、かにかまがちょっと変化してます、分かるでしょうか？
Look, look, see how it's shaped like "what could be inside?" And also here, Kanikama has changed a bit. Can you tell?
え、サメディリアの間違い探しかも...じゃないけどね、微妙に変わっております。
Eh, it's not like a Shark-dillia spot-the-difference puzzle, but it's subtly changed.
なんと、かにかまが増えています！
Surprisingly, the Kanikama have increased!
気づいた？気づいたかな？あとステージ全体はこうなってまーす！
Did you notice? Did you notice? And the whole stage looks like this!
おー、豪華ー！
Wow, so luxurious!
前回よりキラキラ度も増しておりまーす！
It's even more sparkly than last time!
みんなもう応援ありがとう！
Thank you all so much for your support!
それからね、で、でっかいね、サムネイル！かわいい！同じ、同じポ、ポ、なんか違うような気がするけど、あ、同じポーズ！
And then, look, a huge thumbnail! So cute! The same pose... well, it feels a bit different, oh, it's the same pose!
ねぇ、すごい豪華に変えてもらいましたー！
They upgraded it to be so gorgeous!
それから、あ、あーい！白パトちゃーん！
And then, ah, hi! Shiro-Pato-chan!
はいはいはいはい、ちょうどね、はい、あんまりね、あの、出番がなかった白パトちゃんでーす！
Yes, yes, yes, Shiro-Pato-chan barely had any screen time today!
ね、今日はね、1曲目に歌ってくれてどうもありがとうね、白パト！
Hey, thanks so much for singing the first song today, Shiro-Pato!
ね、みんなは白と黒、どっちのパトが好き？
Hey, everyone, which Pato do you like better, white or black?
あーね、あ、白パトちゃんの方がちょっとね、柔らかいの、ほら、跳ねて跳ねて！
Ah, right. Shiro-Pato-chan is a bit softer, look, bounce bounce!
そうなの！やっぱね、パトはね、あの鉄壁のね、ベルトが巻いてあるからね、白パトちゃんの方が柔らかいんですよー！
That's right! Pato has that impregnable belt wrapped around her, so Shiro-Pato-chan is softer!
ほらほら、よく見てみて、2人のツーショット、みんなどっちが好きかな？どっちも好き？
Look, look closely at the two of them together. Which one does everyone like? Do you like both?
あ、ありがとうございます！あ、じゃあ高評価、チャンネル登録もぜひよろしくお願いしまーす！みんな、パトに今日はありがとー！これからもよろしくね！バイバサーイ！
Ah, thank you very much! Ah, please give us a thumbs up and subscribe to the channel! Everyone, thank you so much for today with Pato! See you next time, bye-bye!
生誕祭ライブ終わりました！
つたない歌と豪華なステージで
The birthday live is over!
With modest vocals and a gorgeous stage,
はしゃぐパトが今年もできたのは
あなたのおかげです。
being able to have fun again this year
is all thanks to you.
今日もこの世界に生きていてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for being alive in this world today too!
パトは今いることが一番楽しいです。
Patro is having the most fun right now.
それはきっと世界で一番幸せなことです。
That is surely the greatest happiness in the world.
重大発表あり！ 周防パトラ 誕生日3Dライブ 2025 3D新髪型お披露目 GUEST FUWAMOCO
[Important Announcement! Suou Patra Birthday 3D Live 2025 - 3D New Hairstyle Reveal, Guest: FUWAMOCO]